three things i like about the rogue echo
bumper plates are how thin these 45s are
it's going to create more space on your
loading sleeves they have a solid
durometer rating of 88
and let's be honest they look awesome
i've been getting after it with these
bumper plates for a while so why don't
we go ahead and break down my findings
[Music]
what's up everybody it's jake back in
the barbie garage gym with another
review ready to go for you all today
i've got some rogue echo bumper plates
in this video i'm gonna tell you
everything that you need to know about
these plates from the price and the
features some pros and cons you might
experience and of course who should or
maybe should not add these to their home
gym but before i get going i got to let
you know we've reviewed a ton of bumper
plates on barbin.com if you want to
browse our best list just go and search
barbind best bumper plates and you can
find out for yourself which ones that we
like the best
all right so let's talk about what i
like about these rogue echo bumper
plates first and foremost i already said
they look great and they just really do
i can sit here and stare at them all day
it's just something about the white and
the black contrasting right here just
looks great i also got to say they're
pretty competitively priced compared to
the rest of the market they're right
around in the middle and they're really
solidly built so you're going to get
some really good usage it's a really
solid value right here they have a
really really solid durometer rating of
88 you don't know what i'm talking about
well
adrometer rating is essentially how much
bounce you can expect whenever you drop
your bumper plates so this is going to
range anywhere from 65 up to 100 so
considering these are right at 88 it's a
really solid number right there and i
also love the fact that these 45s are
only 2.4 inches thick so for any of you
out there watching who
you know i'm jealous of who can really
max out either side of your barbell on
those loading sleeves i think you're
really going to enjoy the extra space
that you're going to have with these 45s
on there
[Music]
okay so let's talk about those potential
cons you may experience with these
bumper plates let's talk about money yes
i just said they're pretty competitively
priced that's still true but in terms of
buying a full set
that's where it can start to get a
little bit pricey this is mainly because
you know the heaviest weight is only 260
pounds now that's plenty of enough
weight for me for the most part and for
a lot of you yeah that's still true but
for anybody who needs more than that
well you're gonna have to either
purchase you know one of the lighter
sets or purchase individual pairs and
that's where it's going to get you know
a little bit pricey i really do love the
fact that these 45s are thinner than
most you know 2.4 inches
and that's still great i'm not taking
that back either but
because they're thinner then a lot of
bumper plates out there you do run the
risk of them bending or tacoing on you
some people like to refer it that way
especially if you only have a 45 on your
barbell on either side
and you slam it repeatedly into the
ground you do run the risk of them
bending because of how thin that profile
really is and lastly is the smell now
this might be pretty nitpicky and maybe
i'm being dramatic maybe i'm not but
i pulled these out of the box you know a
little while ago and
they stunk i gotta be honest they stunk
now this is pretty common you know with
rubber in any gym equipment it's gonna
stink a little bit whenever you take
them out of the packaging so i don't
want you to think rogue did something
wrong or weird or fill in the blank
but i have to say you know i've reviewed
a good amount of buffer plates for you
all and i have to say these might be
some of the smelliest ones that i've
unpackaged
[Music]
all right so big sean said it best ain't
nothing more important than the moolah
so let's talk some cash you can purchase
these bumper plates in individual pairs
or as a full set so let's talk about
those individual pairs first and
foremost
the tens are going to run you about 65
bucks the 15s are around 80.
25 pounds those are about 115 bucks the
35s are basically 150 and these 45 pound
plates are gonna be right around
dollars
okay so in terms of the full sets you
only have three different options for
you to work with this is what i was
talking about earlier how it could get a
little bit pricey so that 160 pound set
it's gonna cost you about four hundred
dollars 230 pound sets around 560 and
that 260 pound set that's gonna be
around 640
okay so compared to the rest of the
market with bumper plates
this is pretty average pricing to be
honest it's not that high end of a price
in my opinion but when you compare it to
you know your standard iron plates yeah
they're definitely more expensive but
that's because of the rubber it's an
added feature it's going to extend the
lifespan of the plates you know because
it absorbs the shock and plus you can do
more with bumper plates in my opinion
than you can with a standard weight
plate mainly because of your olympic
lifting now considering the high quality
of this product i think it's a pretty
solid deal in my opinion and they're
going to last you at least 10 years
maybe more than that just so long as you
don't do anything super crazy with them
[Music]
all right so let's talk about the build
now and some of the features with these
bumper plates first and foremost you
have stainless steel inserts in here so
that's obviously really durable but you
also have a virgin rubber coating right
here you know that's going to add to the
lifespan even more like i said these
could last you at least 10 years maybe
even longer if you do in fact take the
proper care of them once again you have
a durometer rating of 88 that's really
solid you know once again 100 is that
highest rate you could have so 88 that's
really solid right there now they do in
fact meet the iwf standard diameter of
17.7 inches but the thickness is going
to vary depending on which weight option
you have so i only have the 45s right
here for you today but 10 pound plates
are eight tenths of an inch thick the
15s are a shade over an inch thick 25s
are right around 1.5 inches thick the
35s are 1.9 inches or so and these 45s
once again they're 2.4 inches thick now
i gotta say these are definitely thinner
than a lot of other bumper plates out
there so
if you know you're able to if you're
strong enough to really max out a
barbell i think these are gonna be a
really good choice for you because
they're gonna create more space on your
loading sleeves now obviously these are
black in color with white lettering
really pops out like i said you know the
contrast looks really good so you can
always see you know which weight you're
grabbing for your workouts but for one
of those people who would rather have
some colored bumper plates rogue does in
fact offer those that's definitely more
of a cosmetic thing you know appearance
thing personal preference it's not going
to change your workout in any way
[Music]
okay so let's talk about those full sets
once again you only have three different
ones for you to work with so those
beginners out there watching you're most
likely going to want to grab the 160
pound set which consists of two tins two
25s and two 45 pound plates so the
difference between the 160 and the 230
pound set is going to be the addition of
two 35 pound plates and the difference
between the 230 and the 260 pound set is
going to be the addition of two 15 pound
bumper plates full sets are always the
way to go in my opinion when it comes to
your best value possible but it's kind
of odd to me that there's nothing
heavier than 260 pounds with these
bumper plates so you're either gonna
have to you know go ahead and buy
another full set or purchase individual
pairs which is obviously going to force
you to spend more money than you
originally intended to if you do in fact
need more than 260 pounds of weight
all right so let's go ahead and do our
quick walk around now with these bumper
plates i'm gonna go and slide this guy
over
let's talk about this profile
i really like the fact there's really
no sign of a seam whatsoever i mean if
you look really up close maybe you can
see one but i really like that you know
a lot of companies will either have a
seam right down the middle or two very
noticeable seams right here on either
side i think you know the lack of that
is going to potentially increase the
lifespan and keep this rubber right here
nice and held together for a longer
amount of time while i've got it turned
like this let's go ahead and showcase
the thickness right here as i said
they're 2.4 inches as you can see it's
just under that two and a half mark
right there so that's really nice and
really be able to add on the plates on
either side of your barbell now
i also mentioned it's 17.7 inches in
diameter so let's go ahead and do that
as well
and yeah it's basically right there
at that 17.7 inch mark so you know it's
nice knowing they do in fact meet iwf
standards and honestly i just love the
look of these like they just they look
nice and clean it's a very basic look
and i just really like the contrast
between the white and the black right
here it's super easy to read obviously
the rogue but also you know which weight
plate you're going to get now some
people might be worried about the paint
right here rubbing off but you know if
that does happen at least the lettering
right here is raised up so i think
you're always going to be able to see
which weight you're selecting
okay so who should purchase the rogue
echo bumper plates well if you are in
fact in the market for some new bumpers
i think you're gonna like the high
quality here because of the stainless
steel and that low bounce rubber these
are gonna last you a really long time if
you're able to power clean an absurd
amount of weight i think you're going to
enjoy how thin these bumper plates are
because it's going to create that much
more space on your loading sleeves for
you and lastly you know once again the
high quality
and considering they're not that
expensive compared to the rest of the
market i think you're getting a really
solid value if you go and snag these
okay so what about the people who might
not want to purchase these bumper plates
well let's talk about how thin they are
yes i know i just said that's a reason
for somebody to buy them i still think
that's true but this mainly is going to
be focused around people who aren't
putting a bunch of weight on either side
of their barbell if you're one of those
people you know you're not lifting a ton
of heavy weight for those power cleans
hang cleans really anything where that
barbell tends to be dropped i'd suggest
looking for some thicker bumper plates
since they do have a decreased chance of
bending over repeated usage and if you
do in fact need more than 260 pounds of
weight i'd either check out some of the
heavier options from rogue or some of
their competitors well friends that's
all i have for you today on the rogue
echo bumper plates i personally love
these bad boys i love the thin profile
it's going to create more space on your
barbell specifically for those elite
lifters out there who are really tacking
on those plates on either side of their
barbell the stainless steel inserts and
that low bounce rubber is going to
create you know a really sound product
and they also have that durometer rating
of 88 so hardly any balance you're going
to experience with these plates right
here
it would be nice if you could have some
other options in terms of the full sets
but at least they're priced super
competitively thanks for watching y'all
i hope this video was really helpful as
you look to add some new bumper plates
to your home gym as always stay on the
lookout for my next review but for now
head over to barbin.com and you can read
more about this product right here just
search bar bend rogue echo bumper plates
review you'll find everything i talked
about here today i'll see y'all next
time
you